

Rod Ellison

Senior Software engineer and Cloud architect



™ Rod.R.Ellison@gmail.com

Parkland, FL. 33076

linkedin.com/in/rodellison

% www.rodellison.net

% connect.unity.com/u/rodellison/column

ABOUT ME

I'm an **IT Professional and Digital Innovator** with over 25 years of diverse **corporate** experience in application development, enterprise architecture, and strategic planning and portfolio governance.

I also have a passion in the development of applications that bridge technologies such as Mixed reality, and Voice with backend Cloud API/Database solutions.

With a strong innovation mindset, I lead by demonstration - researching cutting edge technologies and establishing proof of concepts that provide business value.

SKILLS

- Innovation leader
- Technical mentor
- Effective communicator
- Strategic planning and portfolio governance
- Enterprise Content Management platforms
- (C#, Java, AWS, Unity3D, Blender)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science Florida Atlantic University

AWARDS

AET Digital Exchange innovation 2015- Awarded first place for an innovative eLearning solution using Oculus Rift/Virtual Reality to provide bite-sized video training in a distraction free fully immersed environment.

AET Gold Excellence 2006 - One of 65 recipients (out of 565 technology focused candidates) personally recognized for driving results, demonstrating leadership and delivering value to American Express.

AXP Chairman's Award 2000, Top project (Project Repay).

EXPERIENCE

Staff Engineer

American Express, Sunrise, Florida (April 2016 – present)

Responsible for evolving key American Express Accounts Receivable mainframe and distributed platforms to IaaS/PaaS cloud-based architectures. Additionally, drove the platform's API exposure and CICD maturity.

- Worked with Global Statements team to POC, refactor and begin migration of complex M/F centric application onto the PaaS/Cloud environment.
- Establish a PDF cache repository for hosting Disclosures content for electronic consented Card members, as the first customer of Amex's Cloud based elastic Cloud Storage platform.
- Delivered the first external Statement request flow ('Project Halifax') allowing over 700k newly acquired Citi customers to obtain copies of prior year statements.

Director of Technical Architecture/Staff Architect

American Express, Plantation, Florida (Oct 2013 – Mar 2016)

Drove strategic architecture, and governance for key World Service and Global Credit Administration platforms: Enterprise Content Management/Imaging, Digital Mailroom, Learning Network, Performance/Workforce & Knowledge Management.

- Led creation and refresh of the portfolio's roadmaps and blueprints, influencing and steering approximately ~\$10-20MM annual SQP investment for the collective portfolio and ~\$6-10MM in annual AIU (Infrastructure uplift)
- Team lead in working with Enterprise Architecture to establish the Servicing Company Platform and its 22+ Technical Platforms, including all metrics/goals for over 250+ individual applications.

Lead Technical Architect

American Express, Weston, Florida (2005 – Oct 2013)

- Led migration of a large-scale Document management platform.
- Implemented a SaaS Fax solution for American Express using AT&T/Easylink, defining contractual arrangements and the end to end delivery.
- Architected iVu (Image Viewer Utility), a 2-tier.NET Web Application viewer, providing access to over 35+ repositories housing over 1B documents.
- Designed and built UCID (Universal Customer ID), a Blaze rules-based solution enabling a consistent customer experience in identification verification at point of call.
- Led "Project Repay", building a process allowing 3rd party payment processors a way to upload approximately 500k new customer remit/check images per day for storage in Amex's Document Imaging platforms.